Surya Narayanan

Product UI/UX Designer

Summary

I am a seasoned professional over 5 Year with extensive experience in crafting exceptional visual experience and UX interfaces for digital products solution. My expertise lies in understanding and designing graphic solution based on clients requirement, and translating insights work consistently and accurately. Gathering user requirements, designing graphic elements and building navigation components.

Contact me

Address

Bangalore, KA, India

Work Type

Onsite, Hybrid and Remote

Mobile

+916369724601

Date of Birth

07.18.1998

Website

https://suryadsign.github.io

Linkedin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/surya-narayanan-609339156/

Email

Lgsurya30@gmail.com

Skills

| Figma | **** |
|-----------------------------|-------|
| User Research | |
| Advanced Prototyping | •••• |
| Interaction Design | ••••• |
| Contextual Inquiry | ••••• |
| Cognitive Walkthrough | •••• |
| Design Sprints | |
| Interaction Flow Journey | •••• |
| Accessibility | |

Work History

2021-05 -Present

Product Designer

eMudhra Technology Limited, Bengaluru, India

- Experience in conducting user research and extracting valuable insights to inform product localisation decisions.
- Design and deliver high quality user interactions, experiences, by mapping experiences and journeys, create concepts, Process flows and prototype. Create wireframes on time and to expected level of quality
- Undergone process in ideation / design sprints in diverse, multidisciplinary cross functional teams.
- Expanding the team in crafting and developing our new ventures and products funnel.
- Communicating effectively and collaborate with team members to put ideas (from problems) into action and iterate on them.
- Taking ownership of products and Ability to lead the team, Assign task and Manage the workload.
- Validating the redesigned application as prototype-driven from a user perspective
- Strong Collaboration and Communication Skill with Client/Stakeholders and team mates discussing rough drafts and samples to initiate conversation effectively.
- Creative and professional way projecting graphic designs for the requirements (Images, Sketches, Glf, Logo etc.

Wireframes **User Centred** Design Website **Analytics** Interface Design Design System Visual Design Usability Design **Affinity** Mapping Agile Development Graphic Designs Vector Illustrations Mood Board Logo Brochure/ **Banners** Video Editing Heuristic Evaluation

Tools

Figma
Adobe XD
Sketch
Adobe
Photoshop
Adobe
Illustrator
FigJam
Balsamig

Programming

HTML CSS Javascript

2020-01 - 2021-04

UI/UX Designer

CIOC FMCG Private Ltd, Bengaluru, India

- Developing user friendly interfaces and interaction flows of 10+ applications for mobile and web applications.
- Demonstrated experience proving designs, hypotheses and recommendations through use of data or validated evidence, and providing commercial rationale for decisions
- Collaborating with team for consistency of the user experience while taking it step by step to the next level.
- Worked in SaaS platforms, B2B, B2C and/or enterprise products.
- Executed various visual design stages from concept to final hand-off development.

2019-01 - 2019-12

UX Designer

Haso Technology Ltd, Madurai, India

- Practiced UX research under a senior UX Designer
- Get in touch with stake holders to understand what is the basic requirements and how to develop a product.
- Have strong understanding of User Experience Design and Design Thinking process

Education

2015/08 -2019/05

Bachelor's Degree

Electronics and Communication Engineer

K.L.N College of Engineering, Madurai, India